Drew Pearson Papers
Drew Pearson Papers
1945-1972
Pearson, Drew, 1887-1969
19 linear ft.
Papers of the American newspaper columnist. Newspaper columns (1945-1966) in the form of press releases, as they were distributed to various newspapers.
149464
Biographical History
Columnist and radio and television commentator Drew Pearson (Andrew Russell) was born in Evanston, Illinois on December 13, 1897. He was educated at the Phillips Exeter Academy, Exeter, New Hampshire, and Swarthmore College in Swarthmore, Pennsylvania where he received an A.B. degree in 1919.
Mr. Pearson was the director of the American Friends Service Commission in Serbia, Montenegro and Albania from 1919-1921, an instructor in industrial geography at the University of Pennsylvania and he also lectured on American, Australian and New Zealand chautaquas before he began his career as a commentator. He was the United States delegate to the Atlantic Conference in 1959, he has interviewed many important Europeans and he holds foreign decorations. His publications include Washington Merry-Go-Round (1931), The American Diplomatic Game (1935), and The Nine Old Men.
He is presently (August, 1967) farming in Rockville, Maryland when he is not writing his daily newspaper column, The Washington Merry Go-Round. Mr. Pearson belongs to the Overseas Press Club, the National Press Club, the Overseas Writers' Club and the Cosmos Club of Washington. He has been married twice and is maintaining a residence in Washington, D.C.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The collection consists of Papers and Press releases.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged within series chronologically. At least two separate accessions are represented with duplicate box numbers.
Subject and Genre Headings
Journalism; Pearson, Drew, 1897-1969.; Journalism.; Journalists -- United States.; Newspapers -- Sections, columns, etc.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1945-1989.; Newspaper columns.; Journalists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Papers
  - Papers, 1949 - May 1950 (Box 1)
  - Papers, Jun 1950 - Feb 1951 (Box 2)
  - Papers, Mar1951 - Dec 1951 (Box 3)
  - Papers, Jan 1952 - Sep 1952 (Box 4)
  - Papers, Oct 1952 - May 1953 (Box 5)
  - Papers, Jun 1953 - Dec 1953 (Box 6)
  - Papers, Jan 1954 - Aug 1954 (Box 7)
  - Papers, Sep 1954 - May 1955 (Box 8)
  - Papers, Jun 1955 - Feb 1956 (Box 9)
  - Papers, Mar 1956 - Oct 1956 (Box 10)
  - Papers, Nov 1956 - Jul 1957 (Box 11)
  - Papers, Aug 1957 - Feb 1958; No March 1958 (Box 12)
  - Papers, Apr 1958 - Dec 1958 (Box 13)
  - Papers, Jan 1959 - Aug 1959 (Box 14)
  - Papers, Sep 1959 - Apr 1960 (Box 15)
  - Papers, May 1960 - Jan 1961 (Box 16)
  - Papers, Feb 1961 - Oct 1961 (Box 17)
  - Papers, Nov 1961 - Jul 1962 (Box 18)
  - Papers, Aug 1962 - May 1963; No June, 1963 (Box 19)
  - Papers, Jul 1963 - Jul 1964 (Box 20)
  - Papers, Aug 1964 - Jun 1965 (Box 21)
  - Papers, Jul 1965 - Jan 1966 (Box 22)
  - Papers, Feb 1966 - Jul 1966 (Box 23)
  - Papers, Aug 1966 - Dec 1967 (Box 24)
  - Papers, 1968 (Box 25)
  - Papers, 1969 (Box 26)
  - Papers, 1970 (Box 27)
  - Papers, 1971 (Box 28)
  - Papers, 1972 (Box 29)
- Press releases
  - Press releases, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Press releases, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Press releases, 1948-1949 (Box 3)
  - Press releases, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
  - Press releases, 1950-1952 (Box 5)
  - Press releases, 1952-1953 (Box 6)
  - Press releases, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Press releases, 1954 (Box 8)
  - Press releases, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
  - Press releases, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
  - Press releases, 1957-1958 (Box 11)
  - Press releases, 1958-1959 (Box 12)
  - Press releases, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Press releases, 1960 (Box 14)
  - Press releases, 1960-1961 (Box 15)
  - Press releases, 1961-1962 (Box 16)
  - Press releases, 1962-1963 (Box 17)
  - Press releases, 1963-1964 (Box 18)
  - Press releases, 1965-1966 (Box 19)